[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Who was the first man created by God?",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "reference": "Genesis 2:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What did God create on the first day?",
    "answer": "Light",
    "reference": "Genesis 1:3"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Who built an ark to survive the flood?",
    "answer": "Noah",
    "reference": "Genesis 6:14"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What was the name of Abraham’s son?",
    "answer": "Isaac",
    "reference": "Genesis 21:3"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What sign did God give after the flood?",
    "answer": "Rainbow",
    "reference": "Genesis 9:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Who interpreted Pharaoh’s dreams about the famine?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "reference": "Genesis 41:15-16"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What sea did Moses and the Israelites cross?",
    "answer": "Red Sea",
    "reference": "Exodus 14:21"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Who led the Israelites into the Promised Land?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "reference": "Joshua 1:1-2"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What food did God provide in the desert?",
    "answer": "Manna",
    "reference": "Exodus 16:15"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Who was the high priest when Samuel was a boy?",
    "answer": "Eli",
    "reference": "1 Samuel 1:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 505,
    "question": "According to the Beatitudes who will be filled?",
    "answer": "Those who hunger and thirst for righteousness",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 509,
    "question": "After Jesus fed 5000+ people with two fish and five loaves of bread how many baskets were left over?",
    "answer": "12",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 510,
    "question": "After Jesus fed the 5",
    "answer": "000 how many baskets were left over?",
    "reference": "12"
  },
  {
    "id": 511,
    "question": "After Jesus was arrested",
    "answer": "which apostle disowned him three times?",
    "reference": "Peter"
  },
  {
    "id": 512,
    "question": "After Jesus’ arrest",
    "answer": "one apostle allegedly disowned him three times - who was that apostle?",
    "reference": "Peter"
  },
  {
    "id": 513,
    "question": "And they said one to another",
    "answer": "Behold",
    "reference": "this dreamer cometh Gen 37:19 Who is the dreamer in this verse?"
  },
  {
    "id": 518,
    "question": "Benjamin was the youngest son of which person from the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 521,
    "question": "Complete the following `The light of the body is",
    "answer": "The eye",
    "reference": "Matthew 6:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 524,
    "question": "Complete this verse: \"\"How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of him that bringeth…",
    "answer": "good tidings",
    "reference": "Isaiah 52:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 527,
    "question": "Even though Abram and Sarah were too old what did God promise them?",
    "answer": "A son",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 528,
    "question": "Finish this Proverb: \"\"Labour not to be ",
    "answer": "rich",
    "reference": "Proverbs 23:4"
  },
  {
    "id": 529,
    "question": "Finish this proverb: \"\"Where there is no vision ",
    "answer": "the people perish",
    "reference": "Proverbs 29:18"
  },
  {
    "id": 531,
    "question": "For how long did the flood rain fall?",
    "answer": "40 days and 40 nights",
    "reference": "Gen 7:12"
  },
  {
    "id": 532,
    "question": "For how many days did Jesus appear to his disciples after his resurrection?",
    "answer": "40",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 533,
    "question": "For which type of tree was Lebanon well known?",
    "answer": "Cedar",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 538,
    "question": "How did God appear to Moses in the wilderness?",
    "answer": "A burning bush",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 542,
    "question": "How did Judas end up revealing Jesus’s identity to the Roman officials?",
    "answer": "He kisses him",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 544,
    "question": "How did Moses make bitter water turn sweet?",
    "answer": "Threw a piece of wood into it",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 546,
    "question": "How did Stephanus die?",
    "answer": "Stoned to death",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 553,
    "question": "How long did the flood cover the earth?",
    "answer": "150 days",
    "reference": "Gen 7:24"
  },
  {
    "id": 554,
    "question": "How long was Jesus on the cross?",
    "answer": "6 hours",
    "reference": "Mark 15:25"
  },
  {
    "id": 555,
    "question": "How long was the ark?",
    "answer": "300 cubits",
    "reference": "Gen 6:15"
  },
  {
    "id": 556,
    "question": "How long were the children of Israel in captivity?",
    "answer": "70 years",
    "reference": "Jer 25:11"
  },
  {
    "id": 558,
    "question": "How many books are in the Bible?",
    "answer": "66",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 559,
    "question": "How many books are in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "27",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 560,
    "question": "How many books are in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "39",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 562,
    "question": "How many books in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "27",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 563,
    "question": "How many books in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "39",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 567,
    "question": "How many days and nights did it rain when Noah was on the ark?",
    "answer": "40",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 568,
    "question": "How many days and nights did Jesus fast for?",
    "answer": "40 days & 40 nights",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 569,
    "question": "How many days did God take to create the world?",
    "answer": "6",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 570,
    "question": "How many days did it take God to create the heavens and the earth?",
    "answer": "Seven",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 573,
    "question": "How many New Testament books are there?",
    "answer": "27 books divided into 5 categories",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 574,
    "question": "How many people boarded Noah’s Ark?",
    "answer": "Eight",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 575,
    "question": "How many people did Jesus feed with five loaves of bread and two fish?",
    "answer": "5000+",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 576,
    "question": "How many people were saved on the ark?",
    "answer": "8",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 577,
    "question": "How many plagues are in Exodus?",
    "answer": "Ten",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 578,
    "question": "How many sons did Abraham have?",
    "answer": "Eight",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 579,
    "question": "How many wise men visited the baby Jesus?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 581,
    "question": "How many years of famine did Joseph prophesise to the Pharaohs?",
    "answer": "seven",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 584,
    "question": "How old was Jesus when he began his public ministry?",
    "answer": "30 Years Old",
    "reference": "Luke 3:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 585,
    "question": "How old was Jesus when he tarried behind in Jerusalem after having attended the Passover feast with Mary and Joseph?",
    "answer": "12 Years Old",
    "reference": "Luke 2:41-43"
  },
  {
    "id": 587,
    "question": "How old was Moses when he gave God’s message to Pharaoh: “Let my people go”?",
    "answer": "80 years",
    "reference": "Exod 7:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 588,
    "question": "How were sins forgiven in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Animal sacrifice",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 595,
    "question": "In what city did Mary Martha and Lazarus live?",
    "answer": "Bethany",
    "reference": "John 11:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 596,
    "question": "In what city was Jesus born?",
    "answer": "Bethlehem",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 597,
    "question": "In what language was most of the New Testament given?",
    "answer": "Greek",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 598,
    "question": "In what language was most of the Old Testament given?",
    "answer": "Hebrew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 599,
    "question": "In what water was Jesus baptized?",
    "answer": "River Jordan",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 602,
    "question": "In which New Testament Book does Jesus say \"\"I and my Father are one\"\"?",
    "answer": "Book of John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 603,
    "question": "Is Horeb the name of a town or a mountain?",
    "answer": "A mountain",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 604,
    "question": "Is the Old Testament bigger than the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 607,
    "question": "Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of what king?",
    "answer": "Herod",
    "reference": "Matthew 2:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 610,
    "question": "Many of the New Testament's letters to churches were written by who?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 611,
    "question": "Matthew was a _________",
    "answer": "Tax collector",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 613,
    "question": "Name three of Jesus’ disciples whose names begin with „J”",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "reference": "John and Judas"
  },
  {
    "id": 615,
    "question": "One title that God has is El Shaddai What does it mean?",
    "answer": "Almighty God",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 619,
    "question": "People who pray just to be seen of men are called what?",
    "answer": "Hypocrites",
    "reference": "Matthew 6:5"
  },
  {
    "id": 622,
    "question": "The disciples were on a ship when a great tempest arose and covered it with waves What was Jesus doing at this time?",
    "answer": "Sleeping",
    "reference": "Matthew 8:24"
  },
  {
    "id": 623,
    "question": "The Old Testament was written in which language?",
    "answer": "In Hebrew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 626,
    "question": "Was Goliath a Philistine or an Egyptian?",
    "answer": "Philistine",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 628,
    "question": "What are Paul's letters called?",
    "answer": "The Epistles",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 629,
    "question": "What are the first five books of the Old Testament referred to?",
    "answer": "Pentateuch",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 632,
    "question": "What came first? Elias ascension or Enoch’s rapture?",
    "answer": "Enoch’s rapture",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 633,
    "question": "What day did God create man?",
    "answer": "6th",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 638,
    "question": "What did God divide when He created Earth?",
    "answer": "The light from the darkness",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 640,
    "question": "What did God use the rib of Adam to do?",
    "answer": "Create Eve",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 644,
    "question": "What did Jesus say to Mary and Martha before he raised Lazarus?",
    "answer": "Jesus wept",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 645,
    "question": "What did Jesus say would happen to the temple buildings?",
    "answer": "Be demolished",
    "reference": "Luke 21:6"
  },
  {
    "id": 646,
    "question": "What did Joseph's brothers do after they put him in the pit?",
    "answer": "Sold him as a slave",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 649,
    "question": "What did Moses receive on Mount Sinai?",
    "answer": "The 10 commandments",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 651,
    "question": "What did Solomon ask God to give him?",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 652,
    "question": "What did the Israelites worship when Moses met God on Mount Sinai?",
    "answer": "A Golden Calf",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 653,
    "question": "What did the serpent tempt Eve to do in the Garden of Eden?",
    "answer": "Eat the fruit from the trees that God forbid them to eat",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 654,
    "question": "What does David bring to Jerusalem to bless the religious city?",
    "answer": "The Ark of the Covenant",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 657,
    "question": "What does Paul say is the fulfillment of the law?",
    "answer": "Love",
    "reference": "Rom 13:10"
  },
  {
    "id": 659,
    "question": "What does Simon Peter do for a living before he becomes an apostle?",
    "answer": "Fisherman",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 660,
    "question": "What does Solomon say about sin?",
    "answer": "That no one does not sin",
    "reference": "Ecclesiastes 7:20"
  },
  {
    "id": 661,
    "question": "What does the word gospel mean?",
    "answer": "Good news",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 663,
    "question": "What happened at the moment when Jesus died?",
    "answer": "There was an earthquake and the temple veil tore",
    "reference": "Matthew 27:51"
  },
  {
    "id": 664,
    "question": "What happened first? Jesus’ christening or the feeding of the 5000?",
    "answer": "Jesus’ christening",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 665,
    "question": "What happened first? Murder of Abel or the great flood?",
    "answer": "Murder of Abel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 666,
    "question": "What happened first? The exodus of Egypt or the „fall of Jericho”?",
    "answer": "Exodus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 669,
    "question": "What is the common name given to the first four books of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "The Gospels",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 670,
    "question": "What is the first book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Genesis",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 671,
    "question": "What is the first commandment out of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "You shall have no other gods before me",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 672,
    "question": "What is the Holy Trinity?",
    "answer": "Father",
    "reference": "Son"
  },
  {
    "id": 673,
    "question": "What is the last book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 674,
    "question": "What is the last book in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 675,
    "question": "What is the longest book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Psalms",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 685,
    "question": "What is the second commandment out of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "You shall not make for yourself a carved image; Thou shall not make idols",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 686,
    "question": "What is the shortest book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "3 John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 690,
    "question": "What is the third commandment out of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "You shall not take the name of the Lord your God in vain",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 694,
    "question": "What miracle did Jesus perform at the marriage in Cana?",
    "answer": "Turning water into wine",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 703,
    "question": "What type of insect did John the Baptist eat in the desert?",
    "answer": "Locusts",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 704,
    "question": "What type of tree did Zaccariah climb?",
    "answer": "Mulberry-fig tree",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 706,
    "question": "What was Abraham’s second wife?",
    "answer": "Keturah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 707,
    "question": "What was Abram’s name changed to?",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 710,
    "question": "What was God's promise to never send a flood connected to?",
    "answer": "A Rainbow",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 711,
    "question": "What was God’s sign to Noah that he would never destroy the earth again?",
    "answer": "A rainbow",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 712,
    "question": "What was Hannah’s promise to God?",
    "answer": "To dedicate her son Samuel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 713,
    "question": "What was Harn’s father called?",
    "answer": "Noah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 715,
    "question": "What was Jacob’s brother called?",
    "answer": "Esau",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 716,
    "question": "What was Jacob’s eldest son called?",
    "answer": "Rueben",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 717,
    "question": "What was Jacob’s youngest son called?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 726,
    "question": "What was Ruth’s husband called?",
    "answer": "Boas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 728,
    "question": "What was Sarai’s name changed to?",
    "answer": "Sarah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 730,
    "question": "What was Simon Peter’s profession before becoming an apostle?",
    "answer": "Fisherman",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 735,
    "question": "What was the first of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "Thou shalt have no other gods before me",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 736,
    "question": "What was the first of the ten plagues in Egypt?",
    "answer": "Water turned into blood",
    "reference": "Exod 7:20"
  },
  {
    "id": 744,
    "question": "What was the name of the angel of the Lord who appeared unto Zacharias?",
    "answer": "Gabriel",
    "reference": "Luke 1:19"
  },
  {
    "id": 745,
    "question": "What was the name of the blind beggar at the gate of Jericho?",
    "answer": "Bartimaeus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 760,
    "question": "What was the second plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Frogs",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 761,
    "question": "What was the second son Abraham had?",
    "answer": "Isaac",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 762,
    "question": "What was the secret behind Samson’s great strength?",
    "answer": "He would lose this strength if his hair got cut",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 767,
    "question": "What were Isaac’s sons’ names?",
    "answer": "Jacob and Esau",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 771,
    "question": "What were the two sons of Zebadee (one of the disciples) called?",
    "answer": "John and Jacob",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 772,
    "question": "What’s the final book in the Old Testament called?",
    "answer": "Malachi",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 774,
    "question": "What’s the fourth book of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 779,
    "question": "When Christians observe Palm Sunday",
    "answer": "what biblical narrative are they celebrating?",
    "reference": "Jesus’ triumphal entry into Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "id": 785,
    "question": "Where did a jailer find his faith?",
    "answer": "Philippi",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 786,
    "question": "Where did David work as a shepherd?",
    "answer": "Bethlehem",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 789,
    "question": "Where did Jesus grow up?",
    "answer": "Nazareth",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 790,
    "question": "Where did King Darius order Daniel to be thrown in after he prayed to the Lord?",
    "answer": "The Lion's Den",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 792,
    "question": "Where did Moses receive the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "Mount Sinai",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 794,
    "question": "Where did they live at the beginning of the world?",
    "answer": "Garden of Eden",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 796,
    "question": "Where was Jesus born?",
    "answer": "Bethlehem",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 798,
    "question": "Where was Jesus taken prisoner?",
    "answer": "Gethsemane",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 805,
    "question": "Which apostle was crucified upside down?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 806,
    "question": "Which biblical book tells of David and Goliath?",
    "answer": "1 Samuel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 809,
    "question": "Which book did Jesus directly write?",
    "answer": "None",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 811,
    "question": "Which book reports on the missionary travels of Paul?",
    "answer": "The Acts of the Apostles",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 812,
    "question": "Which books come before and after the gospel according to Luke?",
    "answer": "The gospels according to Mark and John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 813,
    "question": "Which commander had leprosy?",
    "answer": "Naemann",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 814,
    "question": "Which disciple found a coin in the mouth of a fish?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 821,
    "question": "Which illness did Mephiboseth suffer from?",
    "answer": "He was lame",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 824,
    "question": "Which king had a sundial?",
    "answer": "Hezekiah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 826,
    "question": "Which New Testament book gives a prophecy on the end of the world?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 828,
    "question": "Which NT book has Jesus’ Sermon on the Mount?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 837,
    "question": "Which towns were destroyed by fire and brimstone?",
    "answer": "Sodom and Gomorrah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 838,
    "question": "Which two birds did Noah send out of the ark as messengers?",
    "answer": "Raven and dove",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 841,
    "question": "Which type of animal did Balaam ride?",
    "answer": "A donkey",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 843,
    "question": "Who anointed Saul as king?",
    "answer": "Samuel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 844,
    "question": "Who are the religious leaders who constantly tried to trap Jesus with their questions?",
    "answer": "Pharisees",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 847,
    "question": "Who asked Pilate for Jesus’ body after the crucifixion?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 848,
    "question": "Who baptizes Jesus?",
    "answer": "John the Baptizer",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 849,
    "question": "Who begins their book with: \"\"Hear O heavens and give ear O earth: for the LORD hath spoken…",
    "answer": "Isaiah",
    "reference": "Isaiah 1:2"
  },
  {
    "id": 852,
    "question": "Who commanded the sun and moon to stay still?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 853,
    "question": "Who did Abraham have his second son with?",
    "answer": "Sarah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 855,
    "question": "Who did God call out of Ur to move to Canaan?",
    "answer": "Abram",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 856,
    "question": "Who did God tell to build an ark?",
    "answer": "Noah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 858,
    "question": "Who did Jesus teach the Lord's Prayer to?",
    "answer": "His disciples",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 861,
    "question": "Who did Samuel anoint as the first King of Israel?",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 863,
    "question": "Who does God call: \"\"my firstborn higher than the kings of the earth\"\"?",
    "answer": "David",
    "reference": "Psalms 89:27"
  },
  {
    "id": 864,
    "question": "Who had a coat made of camel hair and ate locusts and wild honey?",
    "answer": "John the Baptist",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 866,
    "question": "Who is \"\"the stone the builders rejected\"\"?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "reference": "Luke 20:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 870,
    "question": "Who is the first apostle to deny Jesus?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 874,
    "question": "Who lived in Ur and moved to a country he did not know?",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 875,
    "question": "Who made the golden calf and the bronze snake?",
    "answer": "Aaron and Moses",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 878,
    "question": "Who prophesised the coming of Jesus shortly beforehand?",
    "answer": "John the Baptist",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 879,
    "question": "Who ran to Jesus' empty tomb along with John?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": "John 20:3-4"
  },
  {
    "id": 880,
    "question": "Who recognized Jesus as the Messiah when he was presented at the Temple as a baby?",
    "answer": "Simeon",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 885,
    "question": "Who said \"\"But what things were gain to me",
    "answer": "those I counted loss for Christ?\"\"",
    "reference": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "id": 886,
    "question": "Who said Do unto others as you would have them to unto you?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "reference": "Matthew 7:12"
  },
  {
    "id": 888,
    "question": "Who said to whom: \"\"A person sees what is in front of his eyes but God sees the heart\"\"?",
    "answer": "God to Samuel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 889,
    "question": "Who said",
    "answer": "\"Lord",
    "reference": "if it be thou"
  },
  {
    "id": 891,
    "question": "Who said: „How long will you waver between two opinions?”",
    "answer": "Elijah on Mount Carmel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 892,
    "question": "Who said: \"\"I myself and my house want to serve the Lord!”?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 895,
    "question": "Who takes Jesus’s body off the cross?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 897,
    "question": "Who was Abram’s handmaid?",
    "answer": "Hagar",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 898,
    "question": "Who was Abram’s wife?",
    "answer": "Sarai",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 899,
    "question": "Who was assigned to make a sacrifice in behalf of all Israel during Old Testament times?",
    "answer": "The High Priest",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 901,
    "question": "Who was Caesar when Jesus was born?",
    "answer": "Augustus",
    "reference": "Luke 3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 902,
    "question": "Who was David’s best friend?",
    "answer": "Jonathan",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 905,
    "question": "Who was Joseph’s master in Egypt?",
    "answer": "Potiphar",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 909,
    "question": "Who was the enemy who took the Ark of the Covenant?",
    "answer": "Philistines",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 911,
    "question": "Who was the father-in-law of Caiaphas",
    "answer": "the high priest at the time of Jesus’ death?",
    "reference": "Annas"
  },
  {
    "id": 915,
    "question": "Who was the first man?",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 917,
    "question": "Who was the first son he had?",
    "answer": "Ishmael",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 918,
    "question": "Who was the first son Jacob had with Rachel?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 919,
    "question": "Who was the first woman?",
    "answer": "Eve",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 924,
    "question": "Who was the king of Judea at the time of Jesus’ birth?",
    "answer": "Herod the Great",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 929,
    "question": "Who was the mother of Moses?",
    "answer": "Jochebed",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 933,
    "question": "Who was the Roman ruler when John the Baptist began his ministry?",
    "answer": "Tiberius",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 934,
    "question": "Who was the sister of Moses?",
    "answer": "Miriam",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 935,
    "question": "Who was the tax collector that climbed up a tree so he could see Jesus?",
    "answer": "Zacchaeus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 936,
    "question": "Who watched as Moses floated in the basket down the Nile?",
    "answer": "His Sister Miriam",
    "reference": "Exodus 2:4"
  },
  {
    "id": 938,
    "question": "Who were Adam & Eve’s first children?",
    "answer": "Cain & Abel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 940,
    "question": "Who were the first apostles called to follow Jesus?",
    "answer": "Peter & Andrew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 947,
    "question": "Who wrote the Gospel of Mark?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 949,
    "question": "Whow as the grandmother of Jacob?",
    "answer": "Sara",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1475,
    "question": "After Jesus fed the 5,000 how many baskets were left over?",
    "answer": "12",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1476,
    "question": "After Jesus was arrested, which apostle disowned him three times?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1477,
    "question": "After Jesus’ arrest, one apostle allegedly disowned him three times - who was that apostle?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1478,
    "question": "And they said one to another, Behold, this dreamer cometh Gen 37:19 Who is the dreamer in this verse?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "reference": "Genesis 37:19"
  },
  {
    "id": 1744,
    "question": "When Christians observe Palm Sunday, what biblical narrative are they celebrating?",
    "answer": "Jesus’ triumphal entry into Jerusalem",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1850,
    "question": "Who said But what things were gain to me, those I counted loss for Christ?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "reference": "Philippians 3:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 1854,
    "question": "Who said, Lord, if it be thou, bid me come unto thee on the water?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": "Matthew 14:28"
  }
]